<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on easyAnalizy</title>
    <link>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on easyAnalizy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#003: My Favorite Power BI Visualization Updates of 2024 – Don’t Miss Them! 🚫 </title>
      <link>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🌟Let’s not forget these fantastic updates from 2024. In my view, they’re incredibly useful and have the potential to elevate your reports to the next level. Don’t miss the chance to leverage them and create stunning, impactful dashboards. Let’s dive into the most exciting changes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🔄 Overlapping Layout for Bar Charts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted bar charts to stack and overlap elegantly? Now they can! This feature allows better visual representation of comparative data, especially when showing categories side by side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#001: Append Excel Sheets with Different Layouts Effortlessly</title>
      <link>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll guide you through a simple and efficient way to append Excel sheets with different layouts directly in Power BI. For best practice, I recommend downloading the &amp;ldquo;RawData&amp;rdquo; file provided and following along with each step. By doing this, you’ll be able to apply the instructions effectively and see the results firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/files/RawData.xlsx&#34;&gt;RawData.xlsx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The structure of the file is as shown in the screenshots below. The first few columns in each sheet are the same, while the remaining columns differ – these represent the names of candidates in an election.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#002: 🚫 Don’t Do This in Excel! </title>
      <link>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve discovered Power Query—welcome!&#xA;🌟 It’s like the Swiss Army knife for data: importing, cleaning, and transforming at the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And at first, it’s amazing! But with that first taste of power, new users often get swept up, connecting to folders, stacking transformations like a pro… until chaos ensues. 🙈🙈🙈&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re not careful, you’ll end up with a messy web of queries that’s impossible to pass on, let alone move to a new file location.&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pmirota92.github.io/easyAnalizy/images/002_01.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;h4&gt;The structure of the queries connected the the folder&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
